ABHIJEET KALE

Pune, Maharashtra, India · +91 8356096618 abhi.kale123@gmail.com · LinkedIn · Portfolio

Result-oriented professional with 7 years of experience in Software Performance Testing, Engineering and Analysis. Aspiring to create a distinguished identity for myself through continuous learning and improvement.

EXPERIENCE

DEC 2022 - APR 2023

SENIOR PERFORMANCE TEST ENGINEER - TELUS HEALTH (FORMERLY LIFEWORKS)

- Setting up the Performance Testing Process in the organization.
- Understanding the product and provide performance testing solution.
- Analysing the behavior of system after each deployment cycle.
- Setting up the Apache JMeter framework for Performance Testing Scripting and Execution.
- Developing Python dash plotly based solution to display sprint wise report on internal web page after each execution.

AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

PERFORMANCE TEST SPECIALIST - IBM UNITED KINGDOM LIMITED

- Understanding and improving the performance testing process in one of the projects.
- Resolving Apache JMeter queries in currently established framework.

FEB 2021 – JUNE 2022

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - TEST AUTOMATION - MEDIAOCEAN

- Understanding the product and analyzing the performance testing scope.
- Working with Management, Senior Architect to gather the requirements of the customer.
- Creating the reusable and maintainable performance testing script using Apache JMeter.
- For the execution purpose,
 - o Integrating the JMeter scripts with Jenkins
 - Writing batch scripting to execute from the physical LG machines.
- Writing python script in order to integrate JMeter with Jenkins.

SEPT 2018 – FEB 2021

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT – INFOSYS LIMITED

- Created a Performance testing solution using Python for SAP GUI application with the help of automation tool and integrated it with BlazeMeter.
- Optimized the python code in order to make solution effective.

- Worked closely with development team of SAP Web Plugin to auto correlate dynamic values.
- Point of Contact for all BlazeMeter architecture related questions, sessions and documentations within organization.

AUG 2017 -SEPT 2018

PERFORMANCE TEST ANALYST - ADROSONIC IT CONSULTANCY SERVICE PVT LTD

- Worked in Agile Methodology.
- Decided scope of NFT.
- Gathered requirements for performance testing.
- Created performance testing scripts using Apache JMeter.
- Installed agents in the server for monitoring.
- Handled execution and communication as a part of the project.
- Analysis of the test result.

DEC 2013 - MAY 2015

PROGRAMMER ANALYST - COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

- Created performance testing scripts using LoadRunner.
- Created scenarios and perform executions on Performance Center and Controller.

EDUCATION

SEP 2017

M.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY COLLEGE DUBLIN

JUL 2013

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING ELECTRONICS AND TELECOMMUNICATIONS,

UNIVERSITY OF MUMBAI

SKILLS

- Python, Java, Groovy, SQL
- AWS, Azure, Kubernetes,
- Web and Mobile Application Performance Testing
- Kibana, Solarwinds, Grafana, AppDynamics
- Jenkins, Bitbucket/Git, Jira
- Apache JMeter, LoadRunner, BlazeMeter

AWARDS

- Outstanding Project Delivery Cognizant Technology Solutions.
- Certificate of Appreciation- Infosys Limited
- Tech/Domain Wizard Infosys Limited